A Finding Aid to the Tomás Ybarra-Frausto Research Material on Chicano Art, 1965-2004, in the Archives of American Art AAA.ybartoma
Archives of American Art
- Subject Files, 1965-1997; Series 1
  - Goldman, Shifra, 1978-1994, undated; (5 folders) (Box 12, Folder 8-12)
    (clippings; drafts and final published versions of writings by Goldman; letter to TYF from Goldman, 04/14/1979; TYF notes [for Bibliography of Chicano Art]; Conferencia Plástica Chicana, Austin, Texas, announcement letter to Goldman, 08/05/1979 and schedule; letter to TYF from Goldman, 09/25/1979; note to TYF from Goldman, 12/18/1980, re. letter to Jacinto Quirarte from Goldman, 12/18/1980, cc: TYF; draft of letter to Goldman [TYF's handwriting], undated, re. her CALIFAS catalog essay; International Inventory of Current Mexico-Related Research survey, filled out by Goldman; letter to TYF from Goldman, 09/27/1984; L.A. Artists Call against U.S. intervention in Central America flyers; letter to TYF from Goldman, 06/28/1985; letter to Carolyn [Soto] from Goldman, 04/13/1985, cc: TYF, re. Bibliography of Chicano Art; letter to TYF from Carolyn Soto, 10/04/1985; letter to Lily from Goldman, cc: TYF, 06/28/1985; letters to TYF from Goldman, 08/26/1986, 11/11/1988, 10/06/1994; bibliographic notes; letter to Goldman from Pan American University Press, 01/31/1989, re. Bibliography of Chicano Art, photocopy)
  - Goldman, Shifra - Quirarte Correspondence (see also: Quirarte, Jacinto), 1985-1986 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    (correspondence between Goldman and Jacinto Quirarte, University of Texas San Antonio - photocopies, with note to TYF on 05/16/1985 letter; clippings)
  - Gómez, Ignacio, undated; (advertisement for posters by Gómez) (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Gómez, Marco Antonio, 1970, undated; (clipping; notecard with bibliographic citation) (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Gómez-Peña, Guillermo (see also: Border Arts Workshop; Califas; Fusco, Coco; Muñoz, Celia Alvarez; Lucy R. Lippard Papers), 1982-2003, undated; (5 folders) (Box 12, Folder 16-20)
    (note to TYF from Gómez-Peña, undated; Sara-Jo Berman resume; clippings; performance and exhibition announcements; note to TYF from Gómez-Peña, circa 04/1985 [on back of performance announcement]; letter to TYF from Gómez-Peña, circa 1987; photocopies of art; essay by Emily Hicks [title page and table of contents]; 1987 article by Lucy R. Lippard; writings by Gómez-Peña; writings by Coco Fusco; press releases; Gómez-Peña resume; slides; performance scripts; artist biography; 2 audio cassette tapes: Border Notebook, 1990, and Norte Sur, 1990; poem by Gómez-Peña, "Ocnoceni [in some other place]," 1985; letter to TYF from Coco [Fusco], 11/07/1991; postcard to TYF from Gómez-Peña and Coco Fusco, 12/17/1992; color photograph of work of art; postcards to TYF from Gómez-Peña and Coco [Fusco], 11/22/1992, 03/19/1993; photograph from "The Year of the White Bear")
  - González, Alicia, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    (letter to González from TYF, 07/30-1991, photocopy)
  - González, Aníbal, 1983; (reprint of article) (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - González, José, 1985-1989, undated; (brochure; clippings) (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - González, Louis "The Foot,", 1987-1993; (exhibition announcements; exhibition printed material; clippings) (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - González, Mariano, Jr., 1977-1983; (resume; clippings) (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Gonzalez, Michael, 2000; (clipping) (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - González, Nivia, 1984-1985; (clippings; exhibition announcement) (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - González, Robert, Painter, 1939-1981 (see also: Mexican Museum), 1982, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    (chronology; catalog, Portraits on the Wind: Robert González a Retrospective Exhibition, The Mexican Museum, San Francisco, 1990; clipping)
  - Gonzalez-Day, Ken, 2002, undated (Box 12, Folder 29)
    (clippings; photograph, with note to TYF on the back)
  - Governor's Chicano Issues Conference, Conference, Los Angeles, California (see also: Self Help Graphics), 1980 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    (call for slides; TYF's notes)
  - Graffiti, 1974-1995 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    (exhibition announcements; clippings; books: Kim, Sojin, Chicano Graffiti and Murals: The Neighborhood Art of Peter Quezada, University Press of Mississippi, Jackson, 1995, and Ortega, Gil, The 50's... and Other Assorted Chicano Graffiti, 1981)
  - Graffiti - Slides (see also: Arreguín, Alfred; Brooks, Dudley; de la Rocha, Roberto; Herron, Willie), 1974-1992 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    (slides of graffiti and some miscellaneous art)
  - Greco, Margaret, circa 1989-1991 (Box 12, Folder 33)
    (resume; letter to TYF from Greco, 02/15/1991; research proposal)
  - Greene, Graham, undated (Box 12, Folder 34)
    (2 pages of TYF's notes)
  - Gronk (see also: Mexican Museum), 1985-1993, undated (Box 12, Folder 35)
    (exhibition announcements; catalogs, ¡Gronk! A Living Survey 1973-1993, The Mexican Museum, San Francisco, 1993)
  - Guadalupe Cultural Arts Center (GCAC), San Antonio, Texas (Box 13)
    - General (see also: Lucy R. Lippard Papers; Mesa-Bains, Amalia; Treviño; Vargas, Kathy; Box 30), 1978-2004 (Box 13, Folder 1-23)
      (photographs of art; "poster poems" including "Will not harm the ozone" by Angela de Hoyas; symposium/exhibition announcement, keynote address by Lucy R. Lippard: "Contemporary Art By Women", 1990; class, workshop and event schedules; letter to TYF from Kathy Vargas, circa 12/1983; San Antonio Cinefestival Prospectus and Schedule; theater programs; "call for entries" posters, flyers and brochures; Tejano Conjunto Festival program; GCAC informational packet; exhibition announcements; "Friends of Folk Art," San Antonio Museum Association, flyer; catalogs;; letter to TYF from Linda Cuellar, co-director San Antonio CineFestival 1988, 09/21/1988; San Antonio book fair flyers; membership brochures; letter to TYF from Suzanne M. Sato, Rockefeller Foundation, 05/04/1989, re. funding for GCAC and notes (not TYF's); Latino Caucus Minutes, Oklahoma City, 06/09/1990; TYF's notes [from Latino Caucus?]; note to TYF from Kathy Vargas, 09/18/1991; letter to TYF from Yvette Nieves-Cruz, 06/10/1991, re. Dialogues In Movement: A Chicano Media Arts Retrospective, with enclosures; clippings; letter to TYF from Pedro Rodgriguez, 08/26/1991, re. pre-conference meeting for the national conference of Latino arts and culture and related documents; invitations; National Association of Latino Arts and Culture - NALAC - Newsletter, vol.2, no. 1, March-April 1994; note to TYF from Pablo, 07/09/2001; Christmas cards to TYF from GCAC; GCAC newsletter: vol. 1, no. 8, October 1987; vol. 2, no. 3, January 1988-vol.4 no.6, March 1990; vol. 6, no. 5, February 1991-vol.6, no.8, May 1991; vol. 6, no. 19, July 1991; vol. 7, no. 1, October 1991-vol. 7, no. 2, Novemeber 1991; vol. 7, no. 9, June 1992-vol. 8, no. 3, March, 1993 - there are some errors in the numbering of volumes and issues; The GCAC News [continuation of the newsletter?]: vol.1, no. 1, May/June, 1993-July/August/September, 1993; vol. 2, no. 1, January/February/March 1994; vol. 2, no. 4, October/November/December 1994-vol. 3, no. 2, April/May/June 1995; vol. 4, no.1, January/February/March 1996; vol.4, no. 3, July/August/September 1996-vol. 5, no. 1, January/February/March 1997; vol. 5, no. 4, October/November/December 1997-January/February/March 1998; vol. 6, no. 1, July/August/September, 1998-October/November/December, 1988)
    - Press Releases, 1997, undated (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Tonantzin, Cultural Arts Publication/Newspaper, 1984-2004; (see: Box 31) (Box 13, Folder 25-32)
      (note: volume and issue numbering is inconsistant. Dec. 1983/Jan. 1984 - June/July 1984, vol. 1, nos. 1-4; Jan. - March 1985, vol. 2, nos. 1-2; Jan. 1986, vol. 3, no. 1; May - July 1986, vol. 3, nos. 3-4; Nov. 1986 vol. 4, no. 1; May 1987, vol. 4, no. 2; Nov. 1987, vol. 4, no. 5; May 1988, vol. 5, no. 2; July 1988, vol. 5, no. 3; Nov. 1988, vol. 6, no. 1; May 1989, vol. 6, no. 2; Jan./Feb. 1990, vol. 7, no. 1; May 1990, vol. 6 (sic), no. 2; Oct. 1990, vol. 6, no. 3; May 1991, vol. 7, no. 2; Jan./Feb. 1992, vol. 9, no. 1; May 1992, vol. 8, no. 2; May 1993, vol. 8, no. 4; May 1994, vol. 9, no. 1; May 1995, vol. 11, no. 2; Jan. 2000, vol. 17, no. 1; Summer 2000, vol. 18, no. 2; Fall 2000, vol. 20, no. 2; Winter/Spring 2001, vol. 20, no. 3; Summer 2001, vol. 23, no. 4; August 2002; Spring 2003; Winter 2004; Fall 2004)
  - "La Guadalupana: Images of Faith and Devotion," Exhibition, 1996; (invitation to opening reception) (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Guerra, Luis, 1980-1992, undated (Box 13, Folder 34)
    (letter to TYF from Víctor J. Guerra - Luis Guerra's brother - 01/14/1991; slides; postcard to TYF from Luis Guerra, undated; resume; clippings; color and b/w photocopies of photos of art; biographical information)
  - Guerrero, Antonia, 1989, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 35)
    (exhibition announcement; letter to TYF from Guerrero, 11/15/1992; note card to TYF from Guerrero, 12/09/1992; color photocopy of a photograph of art)
  - Guerrero, Zarco, 1980-1985; (see also: sol Box 30; Día de los Muertos; Goldman, Shifra; Xicanindio Artists Coalition) (Box 13, Folder 36)
    (exhibition announcements; writings by Guerrero; essay by Shifra Goldman about Zarco; clippings)
  - Guerrero, Raúl, 1998; (exhibition invitaion) (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Gutiérrez, Raúl, 1976; (clipping) (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Guzmán, Gilberto, 1979; (clipping) (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Guzmán, Ralph, 1985; (clipping of obituary) (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Haraway, Donna, 1985; (clipping of article by Haraway) (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Healy, Wayne (see also: Los Dos Streetscapers), 1993-2002; (Christmas card, 2001; invitation; exhibition announcements) (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - Hecho En Califas: Festival of New Chicano Performance Arts, 2000-2001; (see also: La Peña Cultural Center, Berkeley; Box 30; oversize poster announcements; exhibition announcement) (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - Hecho en California, Exhibition, University of Guanajuato Gallery, Guanajuato, Mexico, 1981; (press releases) (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - Heisley, Michael (see also: Folklore; Rios, Diego), 1987, 1994, undated (Box 13, Folder 45)
    (note to TYF from Noey Lozano, circa 06/1987 and related note to Noey from Diego M. Rios; letter to TYF from Heisley, 07/18/1987 and enclosed program of a "Mexican Players" performance; letter to TYF from Heisley, 02/25/1994, re. TYF's letter of recommendation and enclosures of Heisley's work - resume, essay/article)
  - Heresies-Latina, New York, Journal, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 46)
  - Hernández, Ester (see also: Galería de la Raza/Studio 24 - Artist Monograph Series; Barnet-Sanchez, Holly), 1981-2001 (Box 13, Folder 47)
    (exhibition announcements; post cards of Hernández' art; catalogs; business cards; letter to TYF from Hernández, 07/13/1993; 2 copies of no. 1 of the Galería de la Raza/Studio 24 Artist Monograph Series, one inscribed to TYF and one to Dudley; clippings)
  - Hernández, John, 2001; (exhibition announcement; catalog) (Box 13, Folder 48)
  - Hernández, Judith E., 1974-1982 (Box 13, Folder 49)
    (photographs; clippings; letter to Clara [?] from Hernández, 05/21/????)
  - Hernández, Los Hermanos (see: Love and Rockets) (Box 13)
  - Hernández, Sam (Sculptor, 1940-), 1981-1997, circa 1987; (resume; exhibition announcements; catalogs) (Box 13, Folder 50)
  - Herrera, Juan Felipe (Poet and Writer), 1981-1990, undated; (see also: Box 30) (Box 13, Folder 51)
    (invitation with note to TYF from Herrara, circa 04/1986; postcard to TYF from Herrera, circa 1988; letter to TYF from Herrera, 11/03/[1987], requesting that TYF write a letter of recommendation for him, with accompanying materials; poem and essay by Herrara; clippings)
  - Herrera, Theresa, 2002; (clipping) (Box 13, Folder 52)
  - Herrón, Willie (see also: Baca, Judith), circa 1980, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 53)
    (resume; TYF's notes on an interview with Baca and Herron; "Los Illegals" printed material)
  - High Performance, Magazine, Los Angeles, Issue 35, vol. 9, no. 3 (see also: Almaraz, Carlos; ASCO; Avalos, David; Baca, Judith; Border Arts Workshop; Carrasco, Barbara; Gamboa, Harry Jr.; Gamboa, Diane; Gil de Montes, Roberto; Gómez-Peña, Guillermo; Gronk; Herrón, Willie; Los Four; Mesa-Bains, Amalia; Norte, Marisela; Romero, Frank; Los Streetscapers; Valadez, John; Valdez, Patssi; Yañez, René), 1986 (Box 13, Folder 54)
  - Hispanic Art in the United States: Thirty Contemporary Painters and Sculptors, Exhibition, Corcoran Gallery of Art, Washington, D.C. and Elsewhere (Box 13)
    - Clippings, 1986-1989; (clippings; press release) (Box 13, Folder 55)
    - General (see also: Goldman, Shifra; Mesa-Bains, Amalia; Quirarte, Jacinto; Ybarra-Frausto Tomás), 1987 (Box 13, Folder 56)
      (letters to TYF from the Museum of Fine Arts, Houston re. TYF's travel to and presentation at the symposium Contemporary Hispanic Art in the United States; TYF's notes, for presentation, from symposium?; essay by Shifra Goldman)
    - Printed Materials, 1987-1989 (Box 13, Folder 57)
      (exhibition announcements; invitations; museum bulletins; magazine; Hispanic Art in Perspective Symposium announcement and brochure)
  - Hispanic Artists, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    (vol. 1, no. 4 of Arts Reporter, 1980 - article, "Hispanic Artists Compare With Total Labor Force")
  - Hispanic Arts News, Newsletter (see: Association of Hispanic Arts, Inc., New York) (Box 14)
  - Hispanic Culture Foundation, New Mexico, 1991-1994; (see also: Box 30) (Box 14, Folder 2)
    (newsletter, El Puente: Winter 1991, vol. 3, no. 1, Fall 1991, vol. 3, no.3, Summer 1992, vol. 4, no. 3, Winter 1992, vol. 4, no. 4, Spring 1993 (vol. 5, no. 1), Winter/Spring 1994 (vol. 5, no. 4); 1992 New Mexico Directory of Hispanic Culture and order form)
  - Hispanic Foundation for the Arts (Box 14)
  - Hispanic Organization of Latin Artists (HOLA), New York, Newsletter, La Nueva Ola, Vol. 1, No. 7, March 1986 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Hispanic Perspectives, Exhibition, Patricia Stewart Gallery, Napa, California (see also: Lomas Garza, Carmen; Vargas, Kathy), 1993; (exhibition announcement) (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Hispanic Photographers (see also: Gandert, Miguel; Photgraphy), 1993; (catalog) (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Hispanic Woodcarving of the Southwest, Exhibition, Smithsonian Institution, Washingtotn, D.C., circa 1993 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    (draft of text for catalog [?]; photgraphs of art)
  - Horsemen of the Southwest, Exhibition, Museum of New Mexico, 1971; (catalog) (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Huarte Goodhue, Lidia, 1992; (resume; flyers) (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Huehuetitlan, Magazine, San Antonio, Texas, December 1985 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Huerta, Benito (see also: Muñoz, Celia), 1984-1997, undated; (2 folders) (Box 14, Folder 10-11)
    (resume; clippings; postcards of art; catalogs; exhibition announcements; photographs of works of art; note to TYF from Celia Muñoz, undated; postcard to TYF from Huerta, 12/01/1992; Art List issues: June-September 1996, Winter 1996-97; invitations; letter to TYF from Huerta, 06/1993; catalog, The Chicano Experience: John Hernandez, Benito Huerta, InterAmerican Art Gallery, InterAmerican Center, Mitchell Wolfson New World Center Campus, Miami-Dade Community College, 1988)
  - Huerta, Dolores, 1995; (Huerta's 65th birthday celebration announcements) (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Huerta, Leticia, 1998; (clipping) (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Huerta, Salomón, Painter, circa 2002 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    (resume; clippings; catalog, Salomón Huerta Paintings, Austin Museum of Art, Austin, Texas, 2001)
  - Human-Ties: Bridging Humanities and Public Life, Humanities project, Center for the Arts, Yerba Buena Gardens, San Francisco, California, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    (letter to TYF from Lorraine Garíca-Nakata, Director of Education and Community Programs, Center for the Arts, Yerba Buena Gardens, 11/01/1996, with enclosed project conept, project components, planning timeline, current Project Advisory and related personnel needs)
  - Humanizarte, Newspaper, San Francisco, California, 1985-1986; (summer, 1986 issue; invitation) (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - "Identity & Community: A Look At Four Latino Museums,", 2002 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    (article from Museum News, May/June 2002)
  - Illinois (see also: Movimiento Artistico Chicano), 1974-1980; (catalog; clippings) (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Image and Identity: Recent Art from "La Reina del Pueblo de los Angeles de la Porcincula," Exhibition, Laband Art Gallery, Loyola Marymount University, Los Angeles, California, 1990; (catalog; exibition announcements) (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Imágenes e Historias/Images and Histories: Chicana Altar-Inspired Art, 1999-2000; (exhibition announcement; clipping) (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Images of Mexico, Exhibition, San Jose Museum of Art, 1980; (exhibition brochure) (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Imagine Publishers, Boston, Massachusetts, 1986, 1989; (publication announcement; subscription forms) (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Immigration/Migration, undated (Box 14, Folder 23)
    (TYF's notes on immigration/migration, 2 pages)
  - Impact of Hispanic Culture in the United States, Conference, University of Iowa, Iowa City, Iowa, 1988; (brochure) (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - In Conversation -- Being Latino, Conference, Los Angeles Public Library, 1994; (conference announcement) (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - In the Heart of the Country/En el Corazón del País, Exhibition, Chicago Public Library Cultural Center, 1991; (catalog) (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Incorporated Artes Monumentales, Exhibition, IAM/Incorporated Artes Monumentales, Denver, Colorado, circa 1981; (catalog) (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Indigenismo, 1984; (clipping) (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - "Infinito Botanica: Enigmatic Divinities,", 1997; (clipping) (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Inside the Loop, Blue Star Art Space, 1998 (see also: Blue Star Art Space), (catalog) (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Installation Art, 1993; (clipping) (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Institute of Hispanic Cultural Studies, Los Angeles, California, 1988; (festival announcement) (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Institute of Hispanic Cultures/Museums, Chicago, Illinois, 1992-1993, undated (Box 14, Folder 33)
    (letter to Alberta Arthurs, Director, Arts and the Humanities, The Rockefeller Foundation, from Oscar L. Martinez, President, The Institute of Hispanic Cultures/Museum, 05/01/1992 with enclosed proposal for funding - statement of history, goals, programs, budget; bound volume; membership leaflet)
  - Instituto Familiar de la Raza, Inc., San Francisco, California (see also: Arreguín, Alfredo), undated, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 34)
    (organizational booklet; letter to TYF from Alfredo [Arreguín], 03/08/1985 with Jan-Feb. 1985 issue of Américas featuring an article on Arreguín)
  - International Arts Relations, Inc. (INTAR) Latin American Gallery and Hispanic American Arts Center, New York, New York (see also: Avalos, David; Baca, Judith; Mesa-Bains, Amalia; Box 30; OV 32), 1985-1996, undated; (5 folders) (Box 14, Folder 35-39)
    (lists of exhibits, 1983-86; letters to TYF re. his participation in various exhibits as catalog contributor and lender, 01/28/1985, 03/03/1986, 11/05/1987; photocopy of letter to Inverna [Lockpez], 02/25/1986, with draft of TYF's essay for catalog; clippings; slides; TYF's notes and type- and hand-written drafts of essays [for exhibition catalogs?]; May 1986 issue of ¡AHA! Hispanic News; Chicano Expressions printed material: announcements, press releases, project description, exhibition checklist, schedule; 25th anniversary printed material: announcements, invitations, program, season calendar, typescript of speech honoring Amalia Mesa-Bains made by TYF)
  - Iturbide, Graciela, 1996; (exhibition announcement) (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - Jaquez, Anna Ruth, 1995-1997 (Box 14, Folder 41)
    (resume; slides; photographs of works of art; postcard to TYF from Pablo [?], 05/17/1997; exhibition announcement; clipping)
  - Jalapeño, Jimmy, 2002; (exhibition announcement) (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - Jaramillo, Don Pedrito, Faith Healer (1829-1907; see also: Barraza, Santa), 1972, 1981-1983, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 43)
    (booklet; clippings; water-color of Don Pedrito; notes to TYF from Robert L. Washington, 01/27/1993, 09/27/1993)
  - Jaramillo, Juanita, Weaver and Historian of New Mexico Weaving Traditions (see also: Mexican Museum), 1982 (Box 14, Folder 44)
    (exhibition catalog inscribed to TYF; lecture/demonstration announcement)
  - Jaramillo, Virginia, 1994; (exhibition announcement) (Box 14, Folder 45)
  - Járdin de Flor y Canto, Art center, Pacoima, California, undated; (clipping) (Box 14, Folder 46)
  - Jerome Evans Gallery, 1985; (sales record) (Box 14, Folder 47)
  - Jiménez, Cisco, 1996; (clipping) (Box 14, Folder 48)
  - Jiménez, Luis, Sculptor, undated, 1969-1996; (3 folders, 1 bound volume) (Box 14, Folder 49-52)
    (postcard of Jiméz' art; clippings; photocopies from catalogs; catalogs; press releases; activity book for children, Laguna Gloria Art Museum, Austin Texas, 1983; catalog, Luis Jimémez: Working-Class Heroes: Images from the Popular Culture, Exhibits USA, Kansas City, Missouri, 1997; catalog, Man on Fire: Luis Jiménez, Albuquerque Museum, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1994)
  - Jiménez Underwood, Consuelo, 1993; (catalog) (Box 14, Folder 53)
  - The Joe A. Diaz Collection, Exhibition, ¡Arte Calíente! The Joe Diaz Collection, South Texas Institute for the Arts, Art Museum of South Texas, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 54)
    (flyer; invitation; South Texas Institute For the Arts summer 2004 newsletter)
  - Joteria Film and Video Program, circa 1994-1995; (event announcements) (Box 14, Folder 55)
  - Journal: A Contemporary Art Magazine, Los Angeles, California (see ASCO), 1987 (Box 14)
  - Journal of La Raza Studies, Journal, La Raza Studies Department, School of Ethnic Studies San Francisco State University, Summer/Fall 1989, Vol. 2, No. 1 (Box 14, Folder 56)
  - Juarez, Benito, Mexican Patriot and Politician (1806-1872), 1969, 1974; (clippings) (Box 14, Folder 57)
  - Juárez, Carolina, 1988; (sale announcement) (Box 14, Folder 58)
  - La Junta de los Ríos: A Fantastic Journey, La Junta de los Ríos: Journey's End, 1996, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 59)
    (installation/exhibitions, Contemporary Culture and Documentary Arts, El Paso, Texas; and exhibition, Sculpture Center, New York. Catalog; exhibition announcement; essay)
  - Juntos Art Association, El Paso, Texas, 1991; (membership form) (Box 14, Folder 60)
  - Just Another Poster? Chicano Graphic Arts in California, Traveling Exhibition, UCLA Fowler Museum of Cultural History, Los Angeles, 2001, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 61)
    (exhibition announcement; UCLA Fowler Museum News, Spring/Summer 2001; Jersey City Museum newsletter, Winter 2003)
  - Kahlo, Frida (see also: Galería de la Raza/Studio 24), 1975-1993, undated; (2 folders) (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
    (TYF's notes from Hayden Herrera's article on Kahlo, and TYF's notes on Kahlo; Frida Kahlo bibliography; clippings; exhibition announcements; photographs of art)
  - Kahlo, Frida - Ideas for Book (see also: Galería de la Raza/Studio 24; Lucy R. Lippard Papers), 1983 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    (1 p. of TYF note's; exhibition announcement; clipping - article by Lucy R. Lippard)
  - Kelley, Ramón, 1973, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
    (TYF's notes on Kelley; clipping; leaflet)
  - Klor de Alva, Jorge, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    (letter to TYF from Klor de Alva, 01/29/1991 - fax - with proposal for TYF's review)
  - Kvinta, Paul, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    (Kvinta's Master of Arts thesis, "Wit, Irreverence, and Counterhegemony: A Rasquache Approach to Barrio Art")
  - L Factor, Exhibition, Exit Art, New York, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    (invitation; public programs schedule; poster; clippings)